Guide to the William R. and Louise Fielder Sheet Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 39. 20th Century Imprints
  - The stars and bars are waving Gilroy, CA: Mary E. Patton,1918 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Words and Music by Mary E. Patton
    Arranged by S. J. Mustol
  - (Ev'rybody ought to know how to do) The tickle toe New York: M. Witmark & Sons,1918 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Lyric by Otto Harbach
  - Central, give me back my dime New York: Charles K. Harris,1905 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Composed by Joseph E. Howard
  - Steamboat Bill New York: F. A. Mills,1910 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Music by Leighton Brothers
    Words by Ken Shields
  - Pullman porters parade New York: Maurice Abrahams Music Co.,1913 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Words by Ren G. May
  - On with Roosevelt march s.l.: s.d.,1936 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Music by Dina Ablamovicz
    Lyric by Margaret B. Code
  - She is ma daisy London: Francis, Day & Hunter,1905.New York: Francis, Day & Hunter ,1905 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Music by Harry Lauder
    Words by Harry Lauder and J. D. Harper
  - Jack Norworth's college medley New York: Norworth Publishing Co.,1910 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Music by Jack Norworth and Nora Bayes
  - Lou'siana song New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co.,1923.Detroit: Jerome H. Remick & Co. ,1923 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Moonlight on the Ganges: fox trot oriental with ukulele arrangement New York: Harms, Inc.,1926 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    Music by Sherman Myers
    Words by Chester Wallace
  - Homeward bound New York: Leo Feist, Inc.,1917 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    Music by George Meyer
    Words by Howard Johnson and Coleman Goetz
  - Billy (I always dream of Bill) New York: Kendis & Paley,1911 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    Music by Kendis & Paley
    Words by Joe Goodwin
  - Roll tanks roll New York: Words and Music Inc.,1942 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    Music by Fred Waring and Jack Dolph
  - Madelon, I'll be true to the whole regiment: English version of the celebrated French soldier's song ÔQuand Madelon' Paris: L. Bousquet,1918.Detroit: Jerome H. Remick & Co. ,1918 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Music by Camille Robert
    English lyrics by Alfred Bryan
  - Old soldiers never die (they just fade away) New York: Charles H. Hansen Music Co.,1951 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Music by Lt. Barry Drewes
  - When day is done: American version based on the European success 'Madonna,' played as a solo New York: Harms, Inc.,1926 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Music by Dr. Robert Katscher
    Words by B. G. De Sylva
  - Love sends a little gift of roses: a ballad New York: Harms, Incorporated,1919.London: Chappell & Co., Ltd. ,1919 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Music by John Openshaw
    Words by Leslie Cooke
  - It's a sin to tell a lie: with additional chorus for piano accordion New York: Donaldson Douglas & Gumble, Inc.,1936 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Music by Billy Mayhew
    Arranged by Pietro Deiro
    Performed by Ozzie Nelson and Harriet Hilliard
  - Love me or leave me New York: Donaldson Douglas & Gumble, Inc.,1928 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Lithographer: A. P. Nickel
    Whoopee
  - Dance of the demon (Damonen-Tanz): grand galop de concert New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co.,1906.Detroit: Jerome H. Remick & Co. ,1906 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Anawanda: march and two-step dance New York: Frank Tousey's Publishing House,1896 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Music by Louis J. Monico
  - Oh, how she could yacki hacki wicki wacki woo (That's love in Honolu) New York: Broadway Music Corporation,1916 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Words by Stanley Murphy and Charles McCarron
  - Roosevelt march: a tribute to the memory of Col. Theodore Roosevelt New York: Will Wood,1919 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Composed by F. Carl Jahn
    Lithographer: Underwood & Underwood Studios, New York
  - What do you do in the infantry: official marching song 264th infantry regiment Hollywood: Saunders Publications,1943 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Music by Frank Loesser
  - The song of the Seabees New York: Robbins Music Corporation,1942 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Lyric by Sam M. Lewis
  - Mister Gallagher and Mister Shean New York: Jack Mills, Inc.,1922 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Music by Ed. Gallagher and Al Shean
  - When old glory leads the nations through the Panama canal New York: J. E. Minnick & Co., Inc.,1914 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Music by Ted Beach
    Words by John Lemon
  - Salome: intermezzo for the piano forte New York: F. A. Mills, Music Publisher,1898.Chicago: F. A. Mills, Music Publisher ,1898 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Music by William Loraine
  - Love I adore you New York: T. B. Harms & Co.,1900 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Music by Harry Osborne
    Lithographer: American Lithographic Co., New York
  - Norah Asthore: ballad New York: T. B. Harms & Co.,1885 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Words and Music by M. J. Cavanagh
    Lithographer: Leon P. Kuhl, New York
  - The band played on New York: The New-York Music Co.,1895.London: Charles Sheard & Co. ,1895 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Music by Charles B. Ward
    Words by John F. Palmer
  - Cuddle up a little closer, lovey mine New York: M. Witmark & Sons,1908 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Music by Karl Hoschna
    Lyric by O. A. Hauerbach
    Three Twins
  - Break the news to mother Milwaukee: Charles K. Harris,1897 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Performed by Hastings & Wright
  - Creep into bed, my baby: a pretty waltz lullaby Cincinnati: J. C. Groene & Co.,1885 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    Words and Arranged by F. Bellasco
  - What a real American can do Chicago: Roger Graham,1917 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    Music by May Hill and Billy Johnson
    Words by Roger Graham
  - December and May, or, Mollie Newell New York: Frank Harding,1893.London: Francis Day and Hunter ,1893 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    Composed by William Loraine
    Words by Ed. Marks
    Performed by Lydia Yeaman-Titus
  - Songs from Hoyt's A trip to Chinatown New York: T. B. Harms & Co.,1892 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    The bowery / words by Charles H. Hoyt, music by Percy Gaunt --The Chaperone / composed by W. Barton --Reuben and Cynthia / words by Charles H. Hoyt, arranged by Percy Gaunt
    Charles H. Hoyt; Percy Gaunt; W. Barton
  - Every boy's a hero in this war today Los Angeles: Ed J. Small, Publisher,1918 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    Music by Chauncey Haines
    Words by Myles McCarthy
  - Uncle Sammy take care of my girl Chicago: Forster Music Publisher, Inc.,1918.Sydney: J. Albert & Sons ,1918 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Music by Jimmie Morgan
    Lyric by Betty Morgan
  - We'll never let our old flag fall New York: John Hanna,1905 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Music by M. F. Kelly
    Lyric by Albert E. MacNutt
  - Every man a king New Orleans: National Book Co.,1935 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Words and Music by Huey P. Long and Csstro Carazo
  - Keep the lovelight burning Chicago: Will Rossiter,1918 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Words by Roger Lewis and Bobby Crawford
  - Catalina is calling me Los Angeles: The Western Music Publishers,1928 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Words and Music by Annette Keyser
  - My yankee sailor boy Los Angeles: Burbank Publishing Co.,1908 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Music by Joseph Montrose
    Words by Oliver Morosco
  - National emblem march for piano forte Boston: Walter Jacobs,1911.Sydeny: W. J. Deane & Sons ,1911 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Music by E. E. Bagley
  - ÔTwas only an Irishman's dream New York: M. Witmark & Sons,1916 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Music by Rennie Cormack
    Words by John J. O'Brien and Al Dubin
    Performed by Blanche Ring
  - Flutter on by my Braodway butterfly New York and Detroit: Jerome H. Remick & Co.,1919 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Music by Sigmund Romberg and Jean Schwartz
    Book and lyrics by Harold Atteridge
    Monte Cristo, Jr.
  - Red wing: an Indian intermezzo New York: F. A. Mills,1907 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Composed by Kerry Mills
  - Hiawatha: a summer idyll Detroit: Whitney Warner Publishing Co.,1902 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Music by Neil Moret
  - You told me to go: song with ukulele arrangement New York and Detroit: Jerome H. Remick & Co.,1925 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Music by Ed Sedgwick, Abe Lyman, and Henry R. Cohen
  - Willow weep for me New York: Irving Berlin, Inc. Music Publishers,1932 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Words and Music by Ann Ronell
  - Hello Montreal New York: Irving Berlin, Inc. Music Publishers,1928 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Music by Harry Warren
    Words by Billy Rose and Mort Dixon
  - Soon New York: New World Music Corporation,1929 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Music by George Gershwin
    Words by Ira Gershwin
- Series 40. Oversize
  - The heathen Chinee Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1870.Philadelphia: Lee & Walker ,1870 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    Also published by John Church, Jr., Cincinnati; C. H. Ditson & Co., New York; J. C. Haynes & Co., Boston; and Lyon & Healy, Chicago. Ex libris Alain de Suzannet
  - The heathen Chinee: song and chorus Chicago: Root & Cady,1870 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    Music by Charles Towner
    Lithographer: Chicago Lith. Co., Chicago
  - View of the Grand Plaza, San Francisco, 1851 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    Photograph of The Grand Plaza, San Francisco, including 'Atwill music store -1851 -1952 at the Grand Plaza and 212 Clay Street in the zinc building better known as 'Salamander Block.' First store was 8' x 14' and was at 158 Washington Street. Third store was #172 Washington Street, and was a fine brick building -see sheet music cover ÔEl Eco del Pacifico.' [from Gleason's Pictorial]'
  - The chaplet: a waltz Philadelphia: R. H. Hobson,[1832].Washington City: Pishey Thompson ,[1832] (Box 58, Folder 4)
    Music by Flora
    includes card with same image, marked 'The Chaplet by ÔFlora', mid-19th century American waltz, Sheet music collections, The Free Library of Philadelphia'
  - Atwill's music establishment, 201 Broadway (Box 58, Folder 4)
    Lithograph 'View on Broadway, St. Paul's Church, Astor Hotel'
- Series 41. William R. and Louise Fielder Ephemera
  - Bancroftiana, no. 78 1981 Jul (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Dichter, Harry correspondence 1947 -1990 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Dichter, Harry Handbook of American Sheet Music n.d. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Fuld, James J. correspondence 1971 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery photographs 1973 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - I was carried away with the music calendar 1972 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Lamson, Jane correspondence 1975 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Last night of Julius Caesar, California Theatre, 1876 Oct 7, broadside 1976 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Leach, Ken correspondence 1971 -1981 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Library of Congress correspondence 1971 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - M. & S. Rare Books 1971 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Martin, Freddy obituary, Orange County Register n.d. (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Morrill, Edward correspondence n.d. (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Morton, David correspondence 1977 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Newsweek, 1971 Nov 1, page 98 1971 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Newton, John correspondence 1981 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Photo-graph re. Sheet music n.d. (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Pierce, Sally. 'The Art of the Music Sheet in Boston, 1825 - 1875' AB 1987 May 4 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Presidential Handbook 1972 (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Society for the preservation and encouragement of barber shop quartet singing in America n.d. (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Tatham, David correspondence 1973 (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - The Sheet Music Exchange 1:1 Winchester, VA: ,n.d. (Box 59, Folder 22)
  - The Sheet Music Exchange 1:3 Winchester, VA: ,1983 Feb (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - The Sheet Music Exchange 1:4 Winchester, VA: ,1983 Apr (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - The Sheet Music Exchange 1:5 Winchester, VA: ,1983 Jun (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - The Sheet Music Exchange 1:6 Winchester, VA: ,1983 Aug (Box 59, Folder 26)
  - Think and smoke tobacco n.d. (Box 59, Folder 27)
  - Two recently discovered portraits of Abraham Lincoln n.d. (Box 59, Folder 28)
- Series 42. Photocopies
  - Albums [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Albums [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Animals n.d. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Automobiles and Airplanes - 20th Century n.d. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Blacks and Minstrels n.d. (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - California - illustrated with original photographs n.d. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - California - non-illustrated 1870 -1879 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - California -- Westward Ho! 1836 -1849 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - California 1880-1889 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - California 1890-1899 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - California, 20th Century (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - California and Hawaii 1850 -1859 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - California and Hawaii 1860 -1869 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - California and Hawaii - illustrated 1870 -1879 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Comic n.d. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Dancing n.d. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Drinking n.d. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Family Groups n.d. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Famous Composers and Operas - 19th Century n.d. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Famous People - 19th Century n.d. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Fashion n.d. (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Fires n.d. (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Flowers n.d. (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Stephen Collins Foster First Editions n.d. (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - L. M. Gottschalk n.d. (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Indians - 19th Century n.d. (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Irish and Will Hays - 19th Century n.d. (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Lithographers and Artists n.d. (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Love, Childhood, Home n.d. (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Military, 19th Century - Confederate imprints n.d. (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Military, 19th Century - general [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Military, 19th Century - general [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Military, 19th Century - General Lafayette n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - 19th Century, general [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - 19th Century, general [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Oversize n.d. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - E. T. Paull n.d. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Places, Events, Things n.d. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Political 1840 -1843 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Pre-1840 Imprints [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Pre-1840 Imprints [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Pre-fire Chicago n.d. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Ships n.d. (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Special Items - 19th Century n.d. (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Special Items - 20th Century n.d. (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Sports n.d. (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Transportation n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - 20th Century - general [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - 20th Century - general [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin and Little Eva - 19th Century n.d. (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - William Vincent Wallace - 19th Century n.d. (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Women n.d. (Box 63, Folder 6)